Gabe Lazo

gabelazo@gmail.com | San Francisco, California, US https://www.linkedin.com/in/gabriellazo

SUMMARY

Experienced devops and enterprise support professional. Spent last four years helping organizations shift into a devops culture, implementing continuous delivery workflows, migrating infrastructure into the cloud and running web services at scale. Also spent over five years supporting business critical enterprise applications from low level troubleshooting, debugging and performance tuning to managing teams, and helping drive business initiatives.

EXPERIENCE

art.com/walmart eCommerce, Senior Devops Engineer

2017-10-30 -- 2019-05-30

https://www.art.com

- Migrated art.com from an on-prem data center to AWS, built and maintained a modern CI/CD infrastructure for maximum agility and re-platformed site from .NET monoliths to modern cloud native java microservices and Node/React frontend applications.
- Provisioned and managed all AWS infrastructure using Terraform across multiple accounts and regions. Developed terraform modules as well as extended off-the-shelf modules for backing services like Redis, ElasticSearch, RabbitMQ and Cassandra.
- Transformed development practices from traditional fixed release cycles to adoption of
 continuous delivery. Championed and evangelized devops culture across various development
 teams, listening closely to developer pain points in order to make improvements to processes
 and systems.
- Implemented CI/CD workflows using Jenkins pipelines, Docker, Helm and Spinnaker. Stressed standards and self-service at every step to enable teams to go from initial commit to production with minimal to zero manual intervention.
- Led devops effort in project to migrate the entire product catalog from Microsoft SQL server to Cassandra.
- Deployed and managed Kubernetes(EKS) clusters for all microservices and backend batch processing using Terraform, Prometheus, AlertManager and Grafana.

macys.com, Devops Lead

2015-08-01 — 2017-10-27

https://www.macys.com

- Led devops team to drive configuration management, build, deployment and monitoring platforms.
- Led project to migrate all application deployment from uDeploy and shell scripts to Chef.
- Designed, implemented and maintained deployment automation from code check-in to production.
- Implemented service dynamic environment provisioning in Google Cloud.
- Led project to migrate all internal devops infrastructure from on-prem data center into GCP.

macys.com, Production Support Manager

2013-04-01 — 2015-07-01

https://www.macys.com

- Managed strategic and tactical day-to-day 24x7 operations of marketing and merchandising applications for macys.com. Managed team in New York to provide rapid response and resolution.
- Built, managed and mentored team of four support engineers, both onshore and offshore.
- Consistently exceed SLA's with customers, maintaining a better than 99.9% uptime
- Established excellent relationships with engineering, business and release teams for more
 effective support services. Served as liaison between engineering team in SF and
 creative/marketing organization in NY.
- Member of round table during critical holiday season that triaged issues across the entire enterprise.

macys.com, Lead Production Support Engineer

https://www.macys.com

- Led team responsible for 24x7 support of marketing and merchandising applications for macys.com. Applications included product information management, photography workflow management, digital asset management and content management systems.
- Successfully supported the migration of bloomingdales merchandising and marketing business onto multi tenant platform shared with macys.
- Collaborated closely with business analyst and product management teams acting as technical subject matter expert for imaging and creative workflow.
- Designed and implemented monitoring tools for production environments that allowed for proactive response and reporting using SiteScope and Splunk.

Nuance Communications, Application Consultant

2009-01-01 - 2010-02-28

https://www.nuance.com

Designed and implemented systems integration solutions for telecommunications platform.
 Worked to upgrade customers to latest release builds. Managed entire project lifecyle.

Sanah Inc, Technical Consultant

2006-02-01 - 2008-06-01

https://www.sanahinc.com

 Designed and implemented systems integration solutions for a telecommunications client using J2EE. Managed an offshore team and was accountable for all their deliverables. Served as technical lead for client and worked to continuously establish best practices.

EDUCATION

University Of California, Davis

2000-09-01 - 2005-12-01

Bachelor - Computer Science and Engineering with Minor in Music

SKILLS

Tools/Technologies (Working Knowledge): Jenkins, Spinnaker, Terraform, Helm, Chef, Vagrant, Docker, Packer, Gitlab, Github, Artifactory, Jira, Confluence, Maven, Prometheus, Grafana, Splunk, NewRelic, Zabbix, SiteScope, ELK Stack, Hadoop, ActiveMQ, RabbitMQ, Consul Application/Web Servers (Working Knowledge): Jboss, Tomcat, Jetty, Apache, Nginx Datastores (Working Knowledge): Oracle, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Redis, Elasticsearch, Solr Languages (Proficient): Java, Ruby, Shell Scripting, SQL, Python Cloud and Operating Systems (Working Knowledge): AWS, GCP, Linux (CentOS/RedHat, Ubuntu), Windows, Mac OS

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish

INTERESTS

Music, Classical Guitar, Sewing, Fitness, Hiking